JUAN MANUEL CERON

<u>Personal Projects</u> <u>LinkedIn</u>

SKILLS

Programming languages:

Java [Spring]
JavaScript
C#
SQL
Python

Frameworks:

Spring
Angular
Testing:

- Junit
- Mockito

Databases:

PostgreSQL MySQL Firestore

Others:

Maven / Gradle
Scrum
Git
Postman / Swagger
JMeter
React
Flutter
GCP

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Native)
English (Advanced)
C1 APTIS TEST
C2 EF TEST

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Systems engineer with 3 years of experience, always focused on creating quality code. My specialty is Java, using Spring Framework, doing tests with Junit and managing code with Git. I have also worked with JavaScript, React, cloud providers and databases like MySQL and Firebase, along with other technologies.

I am a curious, organized and proactive person, passionate about software development, with excellent communication and teamwork skills. I'm always eager to take on new challenges that lead me to a personal and professional growth.

EXPERIENCE

01/2022 - 05/2022

Software Developer

- Development of a web application for medical appointments and management of patients and doctors, using Spring Boot in the Backend (testing with JUnit and applying SOLID principles and best practices), and Angular 12 in the Frontend.
- Development of new functionalities in the Backend of a software product (which allows companies to manage human talent). I was part of a SCRUM team and worked with .NET (C#), ASP. NET (MVC) and SQL Server, using best practices, ensuring code readability and applying design patterns.
- Provided support with bug fixes and legacy code refactoring.

05/2019 - 05/2022

Software Developer (Systems engineer student)

- Development of different applications in Java, applying SOLID principles, with emphasis on the use of data structures such as lists, maps and other collections, implementing persistence through serialization and JUnit for the execution of unit tests.
- Development of web applications using servers on Linux and Windows systems, using Apache and IIS respectively, and deployed using Amazon EC2.
- Development of a Back Office in Java to manage a computer repair shop, implementing user profiles, using the PostgreSQL as database.
- Development of a multiplatform mobile application with Flutter that calculates the cardiovascular risk of registered users, using Firestore as a database, along with a React web application that checks and monitors the data calculated by the mobile app.

Software Developer (Electronic engineering student)

- Development of a Back Office in Java that manages the assignment of schedules and classrooms for the subjects of the electronic engineering program.
- Development of different medium sized projects in Java, applying the principles of encapsulation, cohesion and decoupling.

01/2017 - 07/2017

Application developer in C# for Android Personal Entrepreneurship.

- Development of a video game with real-time interaction between the player, the NPCs and the stage.
- Developed in Unity, implementing in-app purchases and an obfuscator for code protection.
- Use of Autodesk and Blender 3D for the modeling and animation of the main character of the video game.

EDUCATION

Java Full Stack (Spring Boot/Angular),	2022 - 2022
Mitocode Academy, Lima, PER.	2022 - 2022
Java Programing, University of Helsinki, Helsinki, ISL.	2021 - 2021
Scrum Foundation Professional Certificate (SFPC), CertiProf, Remote.	2021 2021
Systems Engineer	2019 - 2022
English Level C1	2017 - 2019